Guide to the Ralph Donnelly papers, 1838-1994 MS2057
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- C & O Canal Association records, 1954-1994; MS2057 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 3, Box 2)
  - Notice of board meeting and minutes with financial and environmental committee reports, 1987 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Along the Towpath vol.19 no.4 contains announcement of 10/24 hike, 1987 October (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Bruce Wood objecting to cost and location of the dinner at the end of the hike and letter protesting method of handling nominations, 1987 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Notice of board meeting with agenda, 1987 November 04-December 06 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of board meeting, 1987 December 06 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Along the Towpath vol.20 no.1 contains notice of annual meet meeting, and calendar of events for the year, 1988 January (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of board meeting with financial and activities report, 1988 February 07 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Minutes of annual meeting, 1988 March 05 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Letter of thanks from Harold Larsen to Ralph Donnelly for dinner and entertainment at annual meeting, 1988 March 07 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Board Meeting Agenda, 1988 April 03 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Letter from Harold Larsen regarding committee to formulate amendment to bylaws, 1988 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Along the Towpath vol.20 no.2 contains Schedule for 34th hike; description of lift bridge at Williamsport. Bruce Wood's final report on hiking the whole canal, 1988 April (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Along the Towpath vol.20 no.3 contains By-laws, 1988 July (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Harold Larsen to Ralph Donnelly thanking him for service on By-laws amendment committee, 1988 October 07 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Minutes of meeting, 1988 December 04 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Minutes of February meeting, 1989 February 05 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Along the Towpath vol.22 no.2 Don Besom becomes editor. Contains announcement of 36th hike and Dick Stanton's, 1990 March (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Along the Towpath vol.22 no.2 contains report on final disposition of the "Douglas Papers", 1990 June (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Hancock News story on abandoned railroad, 1990 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Letter regarding Legal Defense Fund, 1990 October 31 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Notice of meeting with Superintendent, 1990 October 31 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Memorandum regarding meeting with the Superintendent, 1990 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Along the Towpath vol.22 no.4 contains Karen Gray's history of the Level Walkers, 1990 December (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Minutes of Board Meeting, 1990 December 02 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Notice of Board Meeting, 1991 February 03 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Minutes Board Meeting, 1991 February 03 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - List of Candidates for Election, 1991 March 02 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Harold Larsen to Ralph Donnelly regarding reelection to the Board, 1991 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Letter from Dave Johnson, 1991 April 05 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Invitation to Williamsport Lift Bridge gift to National Park Service, 1991 September 12 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Salute to Volunteers Luncheon, 1992 May 02 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Invitation to Hancock Re-watering, 1992 September 19 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - The Frederick Post article C&O rewatering to encourage tourism, 1992 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Letter from Martha Ashelman regarding the C&O Canal Elderhostel course, course schedule enclosed, 1992 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "The C&O Canal and the Railroads" by Patrick Stakem, 1993 March 04 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Letter from Rita H. Bauman to Ralph and Adele Donnelly regarding C&O Canal Association video, 1993 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Letter from Ann Deines regarding Hancock history, 1993 June 09 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Article "C&O Canal Days" in The Antietam Advertiser, 1994 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Application for membership in the C&O Canal Association, Circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Application for membership in the C&O Canal Association, Circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - By-laws of C&O Canal Association, c.a. post, 1959 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Amendment of certificate of Incorporation of C&O Canal Association, 1958 January 30 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Amendment to By-laws of C&O Canal Association, 1961 December 21 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Amendment to the By-laws of C&O Canal Association, 1962 May 01 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Level Walker Report, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Level Walker Report on yellow paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Level Walker Report, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Level Walker Report partially completed, 1989 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Level Walker Report (blank), 1990 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Level Walker Report, 1991 January 25 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Level Walker Short Form Report Sheet, 1983 November (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Level Walker Short form Report Form, 1988 March (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Level Walker Reporting Guidelines, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Level Walker Guidelines, 1988 March (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Level Walker Guidelines, 1989 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Bird/Wildflower Check List, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Plant Checklist, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Statement of the C&O Canal Association on NPS Widewater Plans delivered by Ken Rollins, 1997 December (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Petition to the President of the United States to establish the C&O Canal as a national park, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - C&O Canal Hikes, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - C&O Hikers Reunions, 1955-1978 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - List of hikers on 1954 original Douglas hike, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Publications, 1842-1990; MS2057 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 4)
  This series consists of newsletters, articles, and brochures. The material covers the years 1842-1990. These publications were produced by the C&O Canal Association, National Park Service and individuals such as Thomas Hahn, Grant Conway, and Orville W. Crowder.
  - C&O Canal Report National Park Service and Public Roads to construct Parkway with plates, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - C&O General plan, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Four Locks, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Four Locks 1988 corrects errors, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Community of Four Locks by Mike Mastrangelo, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Official Map and Guide, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Paw Paw Tunnel, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Emergency Directory (issued when McClanahan was Superintendent, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - C&O Canal Historic Structures, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Facts on the C&O Canal, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Volunteer Handbook, Circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Living Wilderness Spring 1954 no. 48 has article and pictures of Douglas Hike, Spring (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Outline Program for the Use and Enjoyment of the Potomac Valley, forward by Justice Douglas prepared by Anthony Wayne Smith, William Davies, John Cover, Grant Conoway C.J.S. Durham, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fifty-Third Annual Report of the President and Directors, 1881 June 06 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hagerstown C&O Canal - Williamsport Bicycle Loop, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - C&O Canal - Sharpsburg Bicycle Loop, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - C&O Canal Boat Replica brochure, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Internal Improvements of the United States Reprint of 1835 issue, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cumberland to Washington on the C&O Canal by Grant Conway reprint in 1954 account of hike, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1984 Miles of Adventure Hikers Guide to the C&O Canal, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Towpath Guide by Thomas Hahn and Orville W. Crowder Section 1, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Towpath Guide by Thomas F. Hahn Section 3, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Towpath Guide by Thomas F. Hahn Section 4, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Springtime along the C&O Canal, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Barron's C&O Canal Directory signed by Dixie Kilham, the owner of Hill Top House, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Condensed Mileage Chart prepared by Orville Crowder, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Flier for "Life on the C&O Canal", 1859 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Copy of article in the Washington Intelligencer"Opening of the Canal", 1850 October 15 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Office of William S. Bryan Jr. Attorney General of Maryland answer to an inquiry regarding sale of canal, 1904 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Mr. Murray Vandimer's objections to the acceptance of the bid of F.S. Lanstreet (W.M. RR) or J.H. Wheelwright (B&O RR) for purchase of the canal, 1904 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Extract from the meeting of the Board of Public Works regarding the sale of the state's share of the canal, 1905 January 04 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Copy of letter of Samuel Rinehart to Sprigg Engineer requesting payment of $1,200.00 due, 1842 July 10 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Brief filed in the Court of Appeals in an attempt to collect a payment of $1,200.00 due, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Barbara Yeaman Christmas Cards scenes along C&O Canal, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous, 1838-1991; MS2057 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 5)
  This series consists of badges, photographs, membership cards, property surveys, and reports. The material covers the time period 1838-1991. These materials relate to the C & O Canal including the Antietam Aquaduct, Little Catoctin Creek, Cadestral, and many of the canal locks.
  - C&O Canal Association Badges various designs, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - C&O Canal Association 10th Reunion Hike Badge, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Membership Cards for the Hancock C&O Canal Club Hancock, MD, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - C&O Canal Association Membership cards for Ralph and Adele Donnelly for years:, 1963-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of Ken Rollins, Deak Stanton, and Nancy Long at Paw Paw Cabin, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Narrative Report of Survey of Lock #44 Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Narrative Report of Cadestral Survey at Mountain Lock (Lock #37) Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Antietam Creek to Mountain Lock (Lock #37) Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Lock 34 to Lock 37 Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Near Weaverton to Lock 34 Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Narrative Report of Cadestral Survey along C&O Canal west of Antietam Aquaduct Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Narrative Report of Cadastral Survey of Maryland Portion of the Harper's Ferry National Monument, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Narrative report Survey from Weaverton Downstream through Brunswick to Little Catoctin Creek Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Narrative Report of Cadastral Survey in the vicinity of Lock 29, C&O Canal National Historical Monument Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Little Catoctin Creek to Lock #29 Property Line Survey done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Narrative Report of Cadestral Survey at East End Monocacy Aquaduct Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Narrative Report Survey at Snyders Landing on the C&O Canal Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Narrative Report Cadastral Survey of NPS property lines from Oldtown downstream to Town Creek Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Narrative Report Cadastral Survey of NPS Property in the vicinity of the Paw Paw Tunnel Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Narrative Report of Cadastral Survey at Four Locks Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Fort Frederick to Ernstville Property Line Survey done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Narrative Report Survey from McCoy's Ferry to Fort Frederick Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Ellis Ellis property line to McCoy's Ferry Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Four Locks to Little Conococheague Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Lock 40 to Thomas Buchanan Line Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Narrative Report Survey from Antietam to Lock #40 Property Line Survey done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Memo on meeting at Four Locks regarding Canal Property Lines Property Line Surveys done along the C&O Canal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Incline Plane Description and drawings of the machinery, track, casson, etc. as built near Georgetown, Circa 1876 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Description of the Ferry Lot along the C&O Canal opposite Shepherdstown, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - C&O Canal, Ft. Frederick to Williamsport guide to the Engineering and Geology G.H. & W.E. Davies, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Pamphlet "Photographs of Western Maryland", 1860-1925 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Spring Box (Spring or Well Protection - Type 1), 1951 February 07 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Analysis of the report entitled "River Bend: The Potential Economic Significance for Maryland prepared by Checchi and Company, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Photo reproduction of Canal Boats of America - Number 8, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - C&O Canal National Historical Park Visitor Information, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Historical Trail information produced by The Boy Scouts of American, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Illustration of "crank.", undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper article "Hermit of Great Falls Thinks 1889 Potomac Flood Was Best" from The Washington Post, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Newspaper article series "Travels on the Towpath" from The Washington Post, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Copy of report by Elwood Morris to C.B. Fisk "Tunnel at the Paw Paw Bends C&O Canal." Has profile showing progress of the tunneling, 1836 December 01 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Copy of Ellwood Morris's report to C.B.Fisk, from the "Tunnel Residency" on the progress of the construction of the tunnel. Has "diagram" giving a very clear picture of the amount of excavation accomplished and the amount remaining to be done. Total length of tunnel 3118 - done 1162 - to be done 1956, December 7, 1838. (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Copy of the surveyor's schematics, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Facts about the Paw Paw Tunnel of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Tunnel Facts, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Section 58 Paw Paw Tunner, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Oversize maps, blueprints, and other architectural information., 1961-1965; MS2057 Series 4; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains maps and blueprints. The material covers the dates 1961-65. These maps and blueprints relate to Town Creek Aqueduct, Aqueduct #7, a topographical map of the Potomac River and C & O Canal in the area of Paw Paw. Also in this series is a list of historic structures compiled by A.W. Franzen.
  - Blueprint of Detail of Closures over Shafts, 1965 January 26 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint of Wood Towpath at North End of Paw Paw Tunnel, 1965 January 26 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Blueprint of Town Creek Aqueduct Nomenclature, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Blueprint of Town Creek Aqueduct showing before restoration, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Blueprint of Town Creek Aqueduct showing after restoration, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Blueprint of Aqueduct #7 over Tonoloway Creek Looking North Hancock,Maryland, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Blueprint of Aqueduct #7 over Tonoloway Creek Looking South Hancock,Maryland, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Topographical map Blueprint of the Potomac River and C&O Canal in the area of Paw Paw, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Blueprint of Plan through Tunnel and of North Deep Cut, 1965 January 26 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Blueprint of Aqueduct #7 over Tonoloway Creek showing adjacent structures and contiguous masonry. Elevation of Towpath Masonry looking South and North from Canal Bed, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Blueprint of Aqueduct #7 over Tonoloway Creek showing adjacent structures and contiguous masonry. Plan, Proposed Work for Historic Structures list made in 1961 by A.W. Franzen (4 sheets) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Ephemera, 1960-1980; MS2057 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series consists of metal buttons and a medallion. These items date from 1960-80. These buttons relate to reunion hikes and tours.
  - Seven Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Association Reunion Hike buttons with Adale Donnelly and Ralph Donnelly name tags, undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Two Oldtown Sportsmen Club Oldtown, MD buttons, 1960 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Two Lowell Mill and Canal Tour buttons, 1980 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 7, Folder 3)
  - One C&O Canal 1828-1924 Williamsport, MD medallion, undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 7, Folder 4)
  - One 17th Annual Reunion Celebration Hike C&O Canal Association Spring Gap to Cumberland, MD button, 1971 May 01 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 7, Folder 5)